Hello friends I wanted to tell you guys
a little bit more about the human brain
organoids and the experiment where
scientists grew the human brain organoid
next to the decapitated spine of a mouse
and it was able to make connections and
use the muscle but first let's talk
about some of the ethical concerns so
the little human brain organoid become
more complex the longer we let them grow
they end up resembling a tiny premature
human brain they even have all the
structures you would imagine in a
developing human brain probably one of
the more concerning things is that a
mature human brain organoid behaves very
much like a premature baby's brain now
the researchers did acknowledge that
they weren't able to do brain mapping of
fetuses prior to birth but if you look
at a 22- week old baby that's the pre-
term EEG you can see very similar burst
patterns and those are just natural
spikes in neural activity that we see in
our brains when we get to be adults
they're a lot more active these brain
waves are similar to deep sleep so the
kind of activ we would have when we're
very much unconscious but I do know what
you guys were waiting for so let's talk
about the experiment so scientists took
the spine of a mouse they placed it on
an air interface the brain organoid was
simply growing near the body over time
it sent out these little dendritic cells
and actually connected with the spine
and grew into it when they sent
electrical signals through the brain
organoid it was able to evoke
contractions in the muscle but when once
it learned to use the muscles it could
do contractions independently the fact
that the brain organoid was able to do
spontaneous contractions is really
really important it shows that it does
have some activity going on that's
probably similar to what's going on in
our brains granted on a very micro scale
this experiment also means that the
brain organoids could be used in
repairing things like spinal damage and
if you guys want to learn a little bit
more about what happened when we planted
a brain organoid into a mouse's skull
and how that actually interfaced I can
definitely do a more detailed video on
that